Paul: 现在轮到我来吐槽一下了
[MUSIC  PLAYING]  PAUL: So it's my turn to get things off my chest I feel.
我最近创建了一个Chrom Dev Summit网站
I recently built the Chrome Dev Summit site.
Jake：我也认为你做了一个非常棒的工作
JAKE: And a mighty fine job I thought you did, as well.
Paul: 谢谢
PAUL: Thanks, pal.
Jake：别客气
JAKE: That's all right.
Paul：但是在我创建这个网站的过程中  我遇到了一些陷阱
PAUL: But on my journey through building that,  I discovered some gotchas.
首先是 --Position Fixed--  告诉我你认为Position Fixed是什么意思
First up-- position fixed-- tell me  what you think position fixed actually does?
Jake：把一个元件从网页本身分离出来 并且把元件放置在与视口（Viewport）相关的位置上
JAKE: Takes an element out of document flow,  and it positions it relative to the viewport.
Paul：什么
PAUL: The what?
Jake：Viewport
JAKE: The viewport.
Paul：Viewport
PAUL: The viewport.
Viewport
The viewport.
Jake：对的
JAKE: Right.
Paul：是的
PAUL: Right.
Jake：我说的对吗
JAKE: Was I right?
Paul：当你把一个会变形的元件的子元件设置为Position Fixed（你得到了另一个会变形的元件）并且这个子元件里面有另外一个子元件也是Position Fixed的时候
PAUL: When you apply a position fixed to a child of something  that has a transform-- so you got  another one with a transform-- and another element inside,  which is position fixed.
Position Fixed的作用会改变
The position fixed behavior changes.
这个会变形的子元件变成了一个新的容器元件
The transformed element becomes a new initial containing block.
Jake：哇
JAKE: Whoa.
真的吗
What?
Paul：是的 它就像一个Viewport里面得一个新的Viewport
PAUL: Yeah, it's like a new viewport inside the viewport.
所以我的做法是  因为我有一些卡片是要变形的  在变形结束后  我按比例改变所有变形的元件  这样才不会看到奇怪的效果  超级烦人的
So the way I did is it, because I  had these cards that were transforming,  at the end of the transition, I'd scale all the transforms,  so that I didn't see weirdness on the content-- so  frustrating.
陷阱2号 -- Pop State
Gotcha number two-- pop state.
Jake：Oh 是的 我曾经用过Pop State
JAKE: Oh, yeah, I've done pop state before.
Paul：恩
PAUL: Yeah.
你知道它会重置滚动条位置吗
Did you know that it restores scroll positions?
Jake：不知道耶
JAKE: No, actually I didn't.
Paul：是的
PAUL: Right.
它也让我发狂
So this is bonkers to me.
你用历史API做一些事情  你把一个state推出来  然后又把state弹走  因为你完全自己操控着APP state
You're doing something with the history API,  you're pushing states on, you're popping states off,  because you're handling app state yourself.
但是浏览器会按照他们的想法来做  我知道你想做什么
But what the browsers all do is they go,  I know what you want to do.
我知道你想重置滚动条的位置去你推出state的时候的位置
I know you want to restore the scroll position  at the point at which you did push state.
但是如果你在做一些异步的事情  对吧
Which is, if you're doing something async, right?
如果你在做一些…… Jake：就是之前我做的所有事情
If you're doing something--  JAKE: Which is what I've always done in the past.
Paul：是的  就是突然的  你的页面会回到它之前滚动条的位置
PAUL: --yeah, then all of a sudden,  your page would just snap down to  its previous scroll position.
我认为我可以修理好它
I thought I can fix this.
我会想些偏方来解决它  手枪
I'll work around it-- gun fingers.
Jake: 嘭 嘭
JAKE: [CLICKING SOUND] pow pow.
Paul：我要做的是为滚动条位置创建一个Listener  如果它在关掉PopState之后改变了    它会滚动一次
PAUL: What I'll do is I'll have a single listener  for scroll position, and when it switches, after the pop state,  it'll do one scroll.
滚回应该的位置
I'll reverse it.
Jake：让它再滚回来
JAKE: Pull it back.
Paul：然后它会像  呵呵  什么都没发生一样 完美
PAUL: And they'll be like, haha, never happened-- shazam.
Jake：是的  Paul：不
JAKE：Yeah  PAUL：No.
因为Chrome是这么做的  它在pop state之后做这个滚动动作
Because Chrome does that-- it does the scroll  after the pop state.
而Firefox是在它之前做
Firefox does it before.
所以你实际上并不知道你是从哪里开始滚动的
So you actually don't know where you scrolled from.
你只是很确定地知道你不是在你之前的位置
You just know that you're pretty certain you're not  in the scroll position you were before.
说到滚动 --最后一个-- Body
Talking of scrolling-- last one-- body.
你知道你不能终止Body的滚动吗
Did you know you can't stop the body from scrolling?
Jake：实际上  那是我下一张专辑的名字 （说笑而已）
JAKE: That's the name of my next album, actually.
Paul：是的 Jake
PAUL: Yeah, Jake.
那太棒了
That's great.
Jake：用鼠标滑轮事件
JAKE: Mousewheel events?
Paul：你可以那么做  但是在移动设备上根本不起作用
PAUL: You could, but that's not going to work on mobile.
Jake：移动设备上 你有触碰事件
JAKE: On mobile-- which you have touch events.
Paul：不是的
PAUL: No.
没有
No.
Jake：那么你就不得不重新去实现所有关于滚动的东西
JAKE: Because then you're going to have  to re-implement all of scrolling.
Paul：是的 所有沿着Y轴移动的内容
PAUL: All the fling physics-y stuff.
Jake：如果你这样做了  你会丢掉性能  丢掉所有的东西
JAKE: And if you do that, you've lost performance,  lost everything, your life.
Paul：算了吧
PAUL: Forget it.
表那样做
Not doing that.
不喜欢那样
Don't like it.
不想要那样
Don't want it.
因为那些卡片又会被扩展
Because what happens, again, these cards, they expand.
需要可滚动的内容在里面
They've got scrollable content inside.
当它们到达可滚动内容的底部的时候  Body会说  我会处理这个
When they reach the bottom of their scrolling content,  the body goes, I will deal this.
现在我要滚动了
I'll start scrolling now.
其实有一个应急方法  开发者能做的  你知道是什么吗
Well, there is an escape hatch, an ability for a developer  to go, you know what?
我想掌控这个
I want to take control of this.
我知道这种情况应该做什么
I know what's supposed to happen here.
我会处理这个
I will deal with it.
可扩展网页会说  吁
So extensible web says, nah.
Jake：吁
JAKE: Nah.
Paul：是吧
PAUL: Right?
是的
Exactly.
好消息是
Good news, though. There is
在Spec Land 在discussion world （不知道指什么）有一个beforeScroll事件  它有一个CSS属性是关于滚动应该被什么中止
In spec land, in discussion world,  there is before scroll, which is an event,  and its corresponding CSS properties around what  scrolling should be blocked on.
但是默认的行为还是和今天一样
But the default behavior still remains as it is today.
它给了开发者更多的选择  我知道我在做什么
It gives developers more options to say, I know what I'm doing.
让我把汽车调到手动挡  Jake：手动挡
Please let me put the car into my manual--  JAKE: Manual.
Paul：或者叫手动变速器  就像它以前一样  我们会从那个状态做起
PAUL: --or stick shift, as it were, and we'll go from there.
所以从可扩展网页的观点来开 耶
So from an extensible web point of view, yay.
Jake: 耶
JAKE: Yay.